Suhas Nana Pote

Assistant Manager | Data Scientist

Mumbai | +91-9702495051 | suhaspote8@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/suhaspote

Summary

Certified Data Scientist with experience of 3 + years in Data Science. Go getter personality with a simple motto in life. If there are things out that are not yet tried, I want to be the first to do it. I learn though experience and not through books. Major strengths include strong leadership and capacity to work as a team player, as well as good communication skills. Self-motivated Analyst who has good organisational skills, is highly efficient and has a good eye for detail. A quick learner who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively.

Work experience

Assistant Manager | Data Scientist
Angel Broking

Data Science Analyst

Aegis School of Data Science

Subject Matter Expert & Research Scholar Aegis School of Data Science June 2015 - May 2017

June 2017 - April 2018

April 2018 - Present

Projects

Dormancy Prediction

R, Python, SQL, Machine Learning, Putty, WinSCP

To predict customers who are likely to Dormant.

Descriptive Analytics 2. Predictive Analytics 3. Prescriptive Analytics

Analyzed 15 months' trade and equity data and predictions made for next 3 months.

Chatbot

Dialogflow (Api.ai)

Developed a Chatbot using Dialogflow. Added Entities, Intents, HTML responses, Image URLs, Quick replies a and Buttons to make it more attractive and user friendly.

FAQs are used for QnA.

Churn Prediction in Telecom company

R, Machine Learning, Hadoop

The objective was to identify the customers who are at high risk of churn using machine learning techniques. Using statistical tool R and Supervised Machine learning classifier - Logistic Regression, created the models using past information to predict the churn possibility of the customers.

Technical Skills

1. Machine Learning

Regression, Classification, Clustering, PCA

2. Languages

R, Python, SQL, C++

3. Big Data frameworks

Hadoop, Spark

4. Tools

Tableau, SAS, IBM SPSS, IBM Cognos BI, IBM Infosphere Big Insight, Anaconda, Qlik Sense, IBM Bluemix, IBM Watson, MS Excel

5. IDE

Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, RStudio, Eclipse

6. Text Mining

Chatbot, Selenium, Natural Language Processing, Web scrapping, Sentiment Analysis, Web automation

7. Internet of Things [IoT]

Raspberry Pi 3B, Arduino, ThinkSpeak, Mosquito Server, Raspbian OS, DHT 22/11 Sensor, PIR Motion sensor

Certificates

- Post Graduate Program In Data
 Science, Business Analytics & Big Data
 In Association With IBM
- 2. Spark and Python for Big Data with PvSpark
- 3. edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Apache Spark
- 4. IBM CE Internet of Things
- 5. Fiber optic

Identifying the most profitable stocks from NSE data

Win SCP, Hadoop -HDFS, Hive

Identified the stocks that a investor will invest in, such that at the end of the year:

- 1. At least his overall capital (Rs 10 Lacs) is protected.
- 2. He makes good profit.

Chatbot for a Business School

Python, NLP, Selenium

I've scraped the FAQs of various section from a Business school's website using Selenium web driver and saved it in a csv file [Questions, Answers, Class]. Then I pre-processed this csv file by stemming and TF-IDF vectorizing the questions. I have used SVM to classify the user's query into different classes. Once the class is found, I defined a subset of questions belonging to this class and then used Cosine Similarity to find the most likely question. The answer associated with the question with maximum cosine similarity to user's query is served to the user.

Student Performance Model

Machine Learning, Python, SQL

Predict the performance of the student based on past data like Grades of completed courses and attendance etc.

Loan Prediction

Python, Machine Learning, Flask

To automate the loan eligibility process based on customer detail provided while filling online application form, Housing Finance company have given a problem to identify the customers segments, those are eligible for loan amount so that they can specifically target those customers.

Sentiment Analysis

R, Text Mining, NLP, Selenium

The goal of this project is to get the insights of the comments and posts from Facebook page. Created a word-cloud to perceive the most prominent terms, where size of each word indicates its frequency or importance. I have created the bar graphs for each emotion.

Theft Detection System

Raspberry Pi 3B, Raspbian OS, PIR Motion senso, Python

Fetched the data from PIR sensor and sent it to the cloud. Displayed and stored the output.

Temperature and Humidity Monitoring

Raspberry Pi 3B, Raspbian OS, DHT 22 sensor ThinkSpeak and IBM Bluemix, Python

Fetched the data from DHT 22 sensor and sent it to the cloud. Displayed and Visualized the data using IBM Bluemix and ThinkSpeak.

Education

Post Graduate Program In Data Science, Business Analytics & Big Data In Association With IBM

Aegis School of Business, Data Science, Cyber Security & Telecommunication

2.75 Grade Points [70 - 75%]

Languages

- 1. English
- 2. Hindi
- 3. Marathi

Passport Details

Passport No. - L7748530

Date of expiry - 09/03/2024

Type - P

Personal Details

Date of Birth - 26/12/1991

Nationality - Indian

Gender - Male

Hobbies - Listening to Music, Travelling, Calligraphy, Cooking, Research

Competencies & Skills

- Tech-savvy
- Creative Thinking
- Analytics Modeling
- Focused
- Excellent Computer competency
- Quick learner
- Flexible
- Good Presentation skills
- Leadership skills
- Good Communication skills
- Problem solver
- Consistent
- Confident
- Team player

B.E. Electronics and Telecommunications S.E.S. G.O.I. F.O.E. - Mumbai University 69% - Final Year

H.S.C. Science [Computer Science]
K M Agrawal College Of Arts, Commerce And Science - Maharashtra Board
78%

S.S.C. Shishu Vikas School - Maharashtra Board 83%
